[In my prime]
[Episode 5]
Si.
Business has been good lately.
They're all parents from the school
coming here to shop.
They even want to pick my brain,
asking how I raise my kids.
Oh, give me a break.
You're full of it.
Si.
Heat this up
for Xin in a bit, okay?
Okay.
Qinglian's got quite the temper.
Whoever ends up
as her daughter-in-law
is in for a rough time.
Grandpa,
Qi Zhi
is still at the sports school.
Besides,
his goal is to be an Olympic champion.
He's not dating.
He's not dating?
Have you ever taken a good look
at Qi Zhi's face?
He has a romantic look in his eyes,
and his cheeks are flushed.
You know what that means?
It means love is in the air for him.
His girlfriend might be someone
we already know.
Romantic look,
flushed cheeks—
maybe that's just
from running.
Oh, you kid.
You still don't believe in fate?
You gotta believe in fate.
No, I don't.
Si,
are you sick?
Why is your face so red?
Well,
it's a bit too hot.
I'm wearing too many layers.
By the way,
I bought you a pair of sneakers.
Try them on later to see if they fit.
No need.
You work so hard to make money.
Take care of yourself.
Don't worry about me.
I have enough shoes.
Qi Shi.
Wash the clothes.
Si.
One, two, three.
You can't get this simple chore right.
What are you good for?
Nothing but troublemakers.
Alright.
Look at all these basins of laundry.
Go help her out.
Go on.
Just wait.
Her helpers will be out in a minute.
Enough.
You two stop watching TV.
Come out quickly.
Wash all these
piles of clothes.
Get some work done.
You guys are all the same—
nothing but troublemakers.
Look.
Here they come.
Impressive.
Dad.
Okay.
We already own a washing machine.
Mom still makes us wash by hand.
What's her deal?
You know how
your mom is.
She just wants to save
on water and electricity bills.
Listen you two,
don't pour the water away later.
We need it to flush the toilet.
Come on, Dad.
Are we really that desperate?
Do...
What are you gossiping about?
Is it that hard to get you
to do some work?
The Qi family
is really interesting.
Every single day,
they're more entertaining
than skits on TV.
Mrs. Huo
is a bit feisty.
Their house is always
noisy and chaotic.
But I don't know why,
I kind of wish our family
could be like that.
Do you remember when we were kids,
Mrs. Huo used to cut our hair?
You were little and couldn't sit still.
Mrs. Huo accidentally
shaved a bald spot
on the back of your head.
You were so vain back then.
Every day,
you wore a hat to school.
I did not.
You don't even remember that?
Mrs. Huo used to
braid my hair
in different styles every day.
I've never
met someone so handy.
She was so good to us too.
Cao Xin.
Hurry up.
You can finish one more math test paper
before bedtime.
Got it.
Sometimes I wonder
if I'm even his real kid.
Even that mean old landlord
wasn't this strict with his workers.
Since when was a mean old landlord
so educated?
He even knows pickled veggies
are bad for you
and mess with your memory.
Fine, don't eat it.
I'll buy you spicy strips next time.
Don't let Dad know.
I'm leaving.
Go.
What are you doing?
I noticed your door was left open.
I closed it for you.
None of your business.
Mind your own.
Mrs. Huo, you're back.
Will you ever stop?
Qi Shi.
You're not done with your chores,
and you have time to watch TV?
I watched it after I finished my chores.
Can vegetables wilt this much
in just two hours?
Do you think I'm stupid?
You're still way too young
to out‑smart me.
No dinner for you tonight!
Fine.
I'm not hungry anyway.
Who wants your lousy pickled veggies?
Who do you think you are?
What are you doing?
Why did you
throw this into their house?
This is outrageous.
We're all neighbors here.
Aren't you embarrassed?
Embarrassed?
He shouldn't overstep.
Busybody. Meddler.
All right.
You've thrown it and scolded them.
Let's go back.
She's in her second year of high school,
busy with studies and homework.
You should cut her some slack.
When does she have time to watch TV
with all that homework?
If she were just slacking off, fine.
But she's practically colluding
with the Cao family.
What nonsense are you talking?
Colluding with the Cao family?
You are blowing things out of proportion.
All right.
I'm telling you,
if you keep spoiling her like this,
she'll never get better.
Who won't get better?
You.
Alright.
Neither of you will have dinner tonight.
Reflect on your actions.
Alright, alright, fine.
Alright, alright.
Go back, go back.
Let's go.
Break it up.
Help me hang this up.
Okay.
Give it to me.
You still want it?
Yes.
It's all dirty.
We can't waste it.
I'll give it to Qi Shi later.
Someday, if Qinglian gets angry again,
she'll throw it back.
Do you know what I call this?
A never-ending cycle.
Dad.
Look.
Where did this come from?
Qi Zhi just sent it.
He told me to keep it
just in case.
I didn't expect it
to come in handy so soon.
We're in this together.
I can't let you go hungry.
Here.
Okay.
Tastes good?
It's delicious.
Slow down.
There's one more.
You're such a good daughter.
I owe you one.
I'll pay you back double later.
Eat as much as you want.
This is pretty hard to open.
Okay.
Slow down.
It's delicious.
Tasty?
This instant noodles tastes
like braised pork.
Dad.
You must be starving.
Easy, easy.
Don't choke.
That hit the spot.
Ah, that's good.
Dad.
We should plan for hard times
in good times, right?
If you eat it all, what about next time?
I can't wait for next time.
I'm starving to death.
At your age,
why are you living so miserably?
Don't worry.
From now on,
I won't be living like this.
Listen,
once my backup arrives,
the two of us
will be eating like kings.
The word ''miserable''
won't apply to me anymore,
got it?
Backup?
Who?
At Hengdong Market,
you can only get rubber bands,
soap,
and things like steel wool.
For stuff like silk stockings
and hair clips,
you still have to go through Li.
Aren't they all wholesale markets?
Li charges higher wholesale prices.
But her merchandise
is really trendy.
Sure, it costs more to stock,
but we can sell it for more too.
You see, every time we
get new stock,
it sells out within three or four days.
With your taste,
if I weren't here keeping you in check,
you'd be stuck
selling soap and steel wool.
What's wrong with my taste?
If my taste was bad,
would I have picked you?
Aihua,
we're out of salt. Go buy some.
Qi Aihua, are you deaf?
Aihua is not deaf.
He's just not here.
Mom.
You...
Why didn't you tell us you were coming?
This is my son's home.
Do I
have to report to you
before I come?
No.
No, that's not what I meant.
Look at all these bags.
We could have picked you up
at the station.
Pick me up?
I'm not that precious.
Aihua was just here.
Blink and he's gone.
He's usually so slow,
but today he bolted off fast.
Mom, Mom,
please, come inside.
Let me help.
Okay.
Mom,
what's all this stuff?
All these bags.
They're so heavy.
Look at you.
You went through all this trouble,
coming all this way
with all these things.
Put them down here.
Sit down and rest.
I'll make you some tea.
I'm not that picky.
Mom, that's cold water.
I'm dying of thirst.
What's that smell?
You're cooking.
Why aren't you watching it?
It's burnt.
I forgot, Mom.
You really don't know
how to run a household.
Mom, let me do it.
This is not how you knead dough.
Your hands, dough and bowl
should all end up clean and smooth.
This needs to be wet.
Aihua doesn't like minced ginger.
But without it,
the filling tastes fishy.
Go get some ginger water.
Forget it.
I'll do it.
Teaching you is more tiring.
Go on, shoo.
Mom,
you've worked so hard.
Don't touch anything in the room.
You don't know how to do it.
Wait for me to clean it up.
I got it.
Done.
Hurry and eat.
Mom, you eat first.
I ate before I came.
I made this for you.
Go ahead and eat.
Why aren't you eating?
Mom, I'm full.
You only ate that little bit,
and you made this much?
Aihua and Qi Shi aren't home.
If you keep wasting food like this,
we'd burn through
every bit of savings we have.
People who waste food
have no blessings.
Truly an unlucky soul.
At my age,
I still have to worry about
this family of yours.
Aihua, you're back.
I'm back.
Wow, honey,
you were quick today.
Got all this laundry washed.
It wasn't your wife who did it so fast.
It was your mother.
Mom.
My dear, sweet boy!
-Mom.
-I miss you so much.
Mom, why are you here?
-Mom.
-I miss you so much.
Mom,
you called last week and said
you'd come in a while.
I didn't expect you to come so soon.
I just missed you.
My good son.
Mom, I've missed you so much.
Aihua,
you've gotten thinner.
Your wife obviously isn't
taking proper care of you.
Only your own mother, I,
will look after you right.
No, Mom, I've gained weight.
Look, my wife feeds me well.
I've gained weight.
I brought you a lot of delicious food.
Great.
I'll fatten you right up.
Here.
This is for Qi Zhi.
Only for your grandson,
not your granddaughter?
Granddaughters will marry
into other families sooner or later.
Why waste the money?
Let's go inside.
Let's go.
Come on in.
Mom, I'm home.
Your grandma is here.
It is not for Qi Zhi.
Don't go around talking about it.
Don't take off your wig.
Come on.
This is like New Year's.
Have some more.
Good.
Delicious.
Here, Sweetie.
Eat up.
Have some dumplings.
Mom,
this is the taste.
This is the taste. So delicious.
In the past, our family was poor.
We kids
all grew up eating
the pickles my mom made.
The taste of childhood.
Slow down.
Here, here.
Don't worry.
There's plenty.
Great.
I am not in a hurry to leave.
I'll stay here
and spend more time with you.
Okay.
By the way,
I also brought two free-range chickens.
When Qi Zhi
is on school break,
have Qinglian cook them.
You're too skinny.
You need to grow.
Eat more pickles.
They go well with rice.
That's enough.
Thank you, Grandma. That's enough.
Mom.
Qi Shi can't eat pickles.
Right.
She can't eat pickles.
Here, give them to me.
I like them.
Your hair…
Why is it black now?
I bought her a wig.
She wears it to school.
You've been at school all day.
What did you
learn today?
I learned
physics and math.
In physics, we learned about particles.
Basically,
large objects
aren't necessarily too big
to be treated as particles.
And small objects
aren't necessarily small enough
to be treated as particles.
Stationary objects
aren't necessarily too still
to be particles.
And rotating objects
aren't necessarily too dynamic
to be particles.
In short,
this frame of reference
is not necessarily stationary.
It's assumed to be stationary.
So...
You just have to analyze
each case individually.
If you ask me,
all these
fancy theories you learn in school
aren't worth much.
I could teach you something practical.
Like what?
On the weekend,
I'll take you to collect scrap cardboard.
Don't look down on scrap cardboard
and empty plastic bottles.
Save them up for a while,
and you can make decent money.
Don't laugh
at my little trade.
Back when times were tough,
your dad brought home money for the family
by collecting scrap.
This is an old‑family skill.
We can't let it die out.
Do I need to learn how to pick up trash?
How about this, Grandma.
If I see bottles after school,
I'll bring them back for you.
There's a lot more to it than you think.
Besides,
this isn't picking up trash.
It's turning waste into treasure.
It's being thrifty.
You've read so many books,
how come you don't understand that?
Mom.
She's in her second year
of high school now,
and her studies are very intense.
You should
just let her
focus on her studies.
Studying is important,
but a girl
also needs to learn
household chores.
Lazy people
have no luck.
Aihua's been at the stall all day.
In a while,
you go get him a basin of hot water
to soak his feet.
Not too hot,
not too cold.
You should
test it yourself first.
Here, Aihua.
Okay, Mom, that's enough.
Enough.
Eat, have more.
Grandma,
you collected all this just this morning?
You're amazing.
This is nothing.
When I was young,
I could collect
22 pounds a day.
Not anymore.
Gotta leave it to you young folks now.
Grandma.
What's this?
A lollipop.
This flavor is hard to find.
I don't give it to just anyone.
You're being so thoughtful.
Very nice.
Sweet?
Sweet.
Grandma,
does that mean
I don't have to collect cardboard anymore?
So that's why you brought me a lollipop
first thing this morning.
You were buttering me up.
Trying to get out of work at your age?
That won't fly.
Lazy people
have no luck.
Don't try to be slick.
You still have to work.
Go,
bring that cardboard over here.
Look at this.
This box was perfectly fine.
They threw it away just like that.
But if you tear it apart,
it's worth money.
Take it.
This...
How much can this sell for?
Your vision
is just like your mother's.
You only see what's right in front of you.
No one buys single scraps.
You have to sell it by weight.
How much more do we need to collect?
What?
Think it's dirty?
If you hate getting dirty,
don't make this money.
Stop being so picky.
You're just spoiled.
You... you don't want this trash,
right?
I'll throw it away for you.
Grandma.
Grandma, let's not take it. Let's go.
Why leave?
There's treasure in there.
But look at how she acted.
Acted how?
Did she give you a dirty look?
Just don't look at her.
Keep your head up.
Are you ashamed of making money?
Making money isn't shameful.
But why do we have to
make money by picking up trash?
Sir.
I'll be right back.
Okay, sure.
No, no, no. Don't.
Grandma, Grandma.
Let's go, let's go.
Take it.
Take it, take it.
Just one sip left. Are you drinking it?
Come.
Qi Shi.
Here.
Come, come, come.
What are you doing? It's so noisy.
You're top of your class at school,
and you're pretty good at
collecting trash too.
I excel at whatever I do.
Every profession produces its own master.
Got it?
Now that you're back from school,
why are you still wearing the wig?
My grandma is here.
My mom won't let me take it off.
How much can you sell
these water bottles for?
Tell me about it.
My grandmother has been
frugal her whole life.
Her lifestyle is totally
different from ours.
I've got a pile of homework,
and she's dragging me out
to pick up trash.
I mean
isn't this just...
Just...
Making trouble out of nothing?
So many bottles.
I don't know
when I'll finish crushing them.
I'll take you somewhere.
Bring your stuff.
Where?
You've gotta help me.
Put them here.
What?
What are you doing?
I spent all day collecting those.
Saving you some effort.
How does this save effort?
Hurry.
Stand back.
Not bad, right?
This really saves effort.
This is great.
This is much better than stepping on it.
How did you
come up with this idea?
I'm just that smart.
Wish you'd put that smarts
into your math later.
Alright.
Okay.
This is
for you.
Take it to the recycling station tomorrow.
You can exchange it for a soda.
What are you two doing?
Go, go, go. Don't.
My bottles. My bottles.
Forget the bottles.
No.
My bottles.
It's so dangerous.
I worked so hard to collect those.
We'll be in big trouble.
-Quick, quick.
-My bottles.
Cao Xin, I'm not done with you.
We worked all afternoon,
and can't even buy two sodas.
It's all your fault.
One bottle.
Fine, I'll crush bottles
for you every day
to make it up to you. Okay?
Alright, you're not all bad.
I've never felt
that soda tasted this good.
Maybe that's why
money you earn with your own two hands
feels especially precious.
Thinking about it,
picking up trash is somewhat meaningful.
You even got a sense of achievement
from picking up trash.
Not exactly a sense of achievement.
Grandma's words are rough,
but she makes good sense.
I mean, at her age,
why would she still bother with this?
What's the point?
She just feels bad for my dad
and wants to help out the family.
Thinking about it,
money earned with your own hands
is never shameful.
Good summary of the main idea.
School's paying off.
But speaking of which,
when is your grandmother going back?
It can't be that every weekend
she drags you out to pick up trash.
Honey.
Come here.
Sit down and try this.
Come, sit here and try it.
Haven't you been complaining
about your backache?
Look,
I bought you a heating pad.
Come, sit down and try it.
It's soft and comfortable.
It's Rainbow brand,
a well-known trademark.
How is it? Is it warm?
Winter is almost over.
Stop trying to flatter me.
Alright,
put it away quickly.
Stop wasting money on useless stuff.
If you really want me comfortable,
get your mom to go back home soon.
Mom's been such a big help
around the house since she arrived.
Isn't that great?
Only you think it's great.
Now when I'm at home,
everything I do is wrong.
Qi Shi is having a hard time too.
She's a tall,
teenager girl,
and she's out there every day
picking up trash with your mom.
Tell me,
if her classmates see her,
wouldn't it be embarrassing?
Her fingernails
get all caked
in black grime.
If Cao Dongfang sees her,
he might think
we mistreat our kid.
Okay.
I'll talk to my mom later.
Also,
your mom likes to stuff the house
full of hoarded things,
just like a garbage dump.
She says
buying in bulk is easier to bargain.
Our place isn't big to begin with.
Right?
Now,
there's barely any room
to even stand.
Alright, honey.
I'll figure something out later.
Try to get my mom to go back early.
Okay?
The Cao family
really has no decency.
So many good clothes,
just thrown away.
Just because you've got money
doesn't mean you can
waste things like this.
Remember what you have to say today.
Aihua, how much did you make today?
How much? I'm not telling you.
Remember
what you have to say today.
Don't worry, honey.
I've got this.
Where did all these clothes come from?
Yeah.
Stop, stop, stop.
Stop.
This...
These are all old clothes.
Why do they smell so musty?
These clothes look
kind of familiar.
Could these be from the Cao family?
No way.
What do you mean no way? Look.
This is a pair of Cao Xin's old pants.
I patched them myself.
You're back from work.
-Mom.
These clothes—
where did they come from?
I picked them up.
They looked perfectly fine,
so I washed them
and was going to put them away.
Mom.
I mean,
the Cao family
threw these old clothes away,
and you picked them up.
You're making us a laughingstock.
Well,
they threw them away,
and I picked them up.
Now they're ours.
Besides,
they're not torn. They're perfectly fine.
Aihua.
Say something. Be the judge.
If we take
the Cao family's cast-offs,
people will think
we're beggars.
I'm telling you,
anyone can look down on us,
but not the Cao family.
Lower your voice.
Keep your voice down.
Mom.
She's got a point.
What bullshit point!
What point?
You've just had it too easy.
You don't appreciate
what you've got.
Back in our day,
forget picking up clothes to wear,
we were eating tree bark
and clay just to fill our bellies.
Alright, alright.
Now you get free clothes
and you won't take them?
Enough, please.
Stop it, Mom. Please.
Honey,
my mom's got a point too.
Mom, don't say anymore.
Anyway,
I won't wear these clothes.
Aihua won't wear them.
Qi Shi and Qi Zhi won't wear them,
and no one in the family will wear them.
You picked them up for nothing.
With the way you waste things,
no matter how big the family fortune is,
you'll burn through it.
I'm telling you,
in this house,
my son is the boss!
Aihua.
Say something, will you?
Honey.
It's just a few pieces of clothing.
Maybe we can just keep them?
You're such a good son.
What are you doing?
Get out of the way.
Aihua, Aihua.
Remember this.
The worst thing
that can happen to a family
is a spendthrift.
This household
still needs me to keep it running.
Okay, Mom.
You're the boss.
Keep them if you want.
Qinglian.
Where are you going?
Let her go if she wants to.
Don't indulge her bad temper.
Anyway, tomorrow,
she'll come back on her own.
Let's go.
Time to eat. Wash your hands.
Let's go, let's go.
Don't spoil her.
Let her go if she wants to.
Hello?
Zhi.
Mom ran away from home.
Where did she go?
I don't know.
She said
she won't come back
until Grandma leaves.
Come on, you should talk to Mom.
Grandma is doing this for our own good.
It's just some old clothes.
You know how Mom feels
about the Cao family.
Those are Cao family cast-offs.
How's that supposed to make Mom feel?
Come on, they are only old clothes.
No need to blow things out of proportion.
You have no idea
how furious Mom was today.
I'm telling you,
don't say this in front of Mom.
She'll definitely be unhappy.
I'm just trying to keep
this family together.
Think about it.
Grandma is already old.
You can't change habits
built over a lifetime.
So you should persuade Mom
to bear with it.
Tell her not to let it get to her.
If I try to talk to her now,
won't I just be walking right
into the line of fire?
They're fighting their own battle.
I'll end up being the bad guy
no matter what I do.
Why don't you go then?
You're just over there talking big.
I knew I couldn't count on you.
I shouldn't have called you.
This Qi Zhi.
Ever since he went to
the provincial sports school,
he's not on the same page
as me anymore.
When you come back,
I'll have a good talk with you.
I wonder if Mom's eaten anything
out there.
Dad,
do something.
What can I do?
You know
your mom's temper.
Those two are at each other's
throats all day.
Who can stop them?
If Grandma doesn't leave,
I'm afraid Mom won't come back.
Actually, your grandma
doesn't mean any harm.
Look at her.
She's running herself
ragged all day long.
She cooked all the dishes
on this table.
We can't bite the hand that feeds us.
How am I supposed to bring myself
to tell your grandmother to go back?
Then you...
Here.
Mom,
take a rest.
It's fine. You guys eat.
Look.
Your grandma
collects garbage outside all day
and doesn't earn much,
but she never keeps it for herself.
She keeps bringing home baskets of fruit
for the family.
Let's put it this way.
Since your grandma came,
have you ever gone hungry?
Have you ever washed dirty clothes?
I don't want to come home
exhausted from working all day,
only to mop floors and wash dishes.
Just think of your grandma
as a bonus for our family.
And your mom
gets to rest at her parents' house.
Listen to yourself.
Would you dare say that
to Mom's face?
We are grateful Grandma tries her hardest.
But it's still really tough on us.
She forced...
Look.
She forced me to collect cardboard
and bottles.
Look at my hands.
Look.
If it weren't for Cao Xin,
I would've crushed my fingernails.
My mom has a sharp tongue,
but she never forces us
to do everything.
Even when she punishes me,
it's because I did something wrong.
There's a reason for it.
I never thought
it would come to this.
I miss my mom.
You think I don't miss her too?
But you feel bad for your mom,
and I feel bad for mine too.
I can't just say
we should kick Grandma out.
I can't bring myself to say it.
You know who's really stuck in the middle?
Me.
I've got it the hardest.
Whose house is this?
What is this smell?
Grandpa,
do you smell that?
I smell it.
It's almost knocking me out.
It stinks.
That old lady from the Qi family
is quite a character.
She's a master.
Qinglian's tough as nails,
and she still got run off.
I guess
this smell has something to do with her.
What should we do?
We just have to put up with it?
Don't worry.
Someone will deal with her.
Just wait and see
how this plays out.
Come in.
Close the door.
I'm going out to read for a while.
It smells too bad inside.
Why does it stink so much?
What is this?
What is this smell?
It smells a bit like...
Well...
It stinks.
Nonsense.
It doesn't stink at all.
This thing
smells bad but tastes good.
Your dad loves pickles.
The ones sold in town aren't authentic.
So,
I've been busy fermenting several crocks
to satisfy his craving.
Grandma,
our health textbook says
eating pickled food all the time
is bad for our health.
Nonsense.
I've eaten pickles all my life.
I don't feel anything wrong.
Don't listen to them.
Listen to me.
Mom,
how about you make a little less?
We can't eat it all.
We really can't eat that much.
Besides,
this smell is too strong.
Right.
Grandma,
the neighbors
will complain.
That's perfect.
Then I'll make more.
I'll give some to everyone
except that Cao family.
Once they taste how good it is,
they won't complain any more.
Hard is the way, hard is the way.
So many forks, where do I stray?
A time will come to ride the wind
and cleave the waves.
Set sail straight across the vast sea.
A golden goblet of fine wine
costs ten thousand coins.
A jade plate of delicacies
worth ten thousand more.
I lay down my cup,
drop my chopsticks, cannot eat.
Draw my sword, look all around,
my heart adrift.
Why are you out so late?
Why are you out?
You know why.
The smell from your house is too strong.
I never knew your grandma
could have this much impact.
Your mom really can't handle her?
My mom was so upset she left.
It's not that we don't want to step in.
We really can't.
You know, my grandma
isn't a bad person.
Everything she does,
she does for us.
She just doesn't realize
that her way of living
is completely different from ours.
Living together
is just uncomfortable.
Just like my grandfather.
He used to insist on
eating leftovers,
and he'd never throw out expired food
because he hated wasting anything.
Until he ended up in the hospital
and spent hundreds on gastroenteritis.
Then he realized
that sometimes being thrifty
is just another kind of waste.
Once your grandmother realizes
that she's causing
trouble for you,
she'll leave on her own.
You mean...